<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<page title="Construo - A 2D Construction Toy">
  <section title="News">
    <news>
      <item date="30. May 2010">
        Small webpage layout update
      </item>

      <item date="29. Jul 2003">
        Construo 0.2.2 is out, fixes the speed problems in de X11
        target, should result in around 4 times smoother graphics
      </item>

      <item date="26. Jul 2003">
        Construo 0.2.1 is out, some new features and lots of bugfixes. A
        (incomplete) <a href="tutorial.html">tutorial</a> is also
        available.
      </item>

      <item date="11. Jan 2003">
        Construo 0.2.0 is out, new features, new bugs
      </item>

      <item date="02. Dez 2002">
        Construo House of Horrors - Part 2 released, a pack of 9
        new torture constructions by Mark Michelsen is
        available
      </item>

      <item date="24. Nov 2002">
        Construo House of Horrors, a pack of 9 torture constructions by
        Mark Michelsen is available
      </item>

      <item date="22. Nov 2002">
        Construo 0.1.0 is out
      </item>
    </news> 
  </section>

  <section title="Introduction">
    Construo is a simple 2D construction programm (it is currently
    not a real game) for objects which consist of rods and springs
    and let them react on physical forces. You can currently
    construct buildings and objects like bridges, towers,
    spaceshuttles, etc. and you let them fall to ground and see seem
    smash and break. Sound like fun, doesn't it =;-)
    
    The game is similar to <link
                              ref="http://www.bridgebuilder-game.com/bbg-info.php">Bridge Builder</link> and
    heavily inspired from the <link
                                 ref="http://www.gamasutra.com">Gamasutra</link> article <link
                                                                                            ref="http://www.gamasutra.com/features/20000208/lander_01.htm">Collision
      Response: Bouncy, Trouncy, Fun</link>. Its covered under the
    <link ref="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl.html">GNU General
      Public License</link>, thats means source code is availabel and
    you are allowed to modify it.
  </section>

  <section title="ToDo">
    The 'thing' is currently useable for constructing simple 2D
    objects, but there is really quite a lot stuff missing. There is
    currently no way to set different parameters for rods or springs,
    change their color or thikness. Building with prefabs could also
    be fun. Colliding rods would also be a usefull feature, currently
    only rod-ground collision is implemented. See the file <tt><a href="http://savannah.nongnu.org/cgi-bin/viewcvs/*checkout*/construo/construo/TODO?rev=HEAD&amp;content-type=text/plain">TODO</a></tt> 
    in the source directory contains a few more infos.
  </section>

  <section title="Requirements">
    <dl>
      <dt>OS:</dt><dd>GNU/Linux or another Unix-like OS</dd>
      <dt>CPU:</dt><dd>probally something fast, havn't tested it on anything sub-1Ghz</dd>
      <dt>Libraries:</dt><dd>Only plain Xlib is required, which comes with every distro</dd>
    </dl>
  </section>
  
  <section title="Screenshots">
    <screenshots>
      <item>screenshot_0.2.0</item>
      <item>screenshot_0.2.0-1</item>
      <item>screenshot_0.2.0-2</item>
      <item>screenshot6</item>
      <item>screenshot5</item>
      <item>screenshot4</item>
      <item>screenshot3</item>
      <item>screenshot1</item>
      <item>screenshot2</item>
    </screenshots>
  </section>

  <section title="Download">
    <subsection title="Source Code">
      The versions up from 0.1.0 only require Xlib or Glut, which
      comes with every GNU/Linux and should be available an almost all
      systems, so you shouldn't have problems compiling it. Binary
      version for 0.2.0 arn't planed, but can be provided if anybody
      has throuble compiling themself.

      <downloads>
        <item file="construo-0.2.2.tar.gz">most current release, see  <a href="http://savannah.nongnu.org/cgi-bin/viewcvs/*checkout*/construo/construo/NEWS?rev=release_0_2_2&amp;content-type=text/plain">NEWS</a> for more info</item>
	<item file="construo-0.2.1.tar.gz"/>
	<item file="construo-0.2.0.tar.gz"/>
	<item file="construo-0.1.0.tar.gz"/>
	<item file="construo-0.0.2.tar.gz"/>
	<item file="construo-0.0.1.tar.gz"/>
      </downloads>
    </subsection>

    <subsection title="SVN Access">
      <tt>svn checkout http://svn.berlios.de/svnroot/repos/construo/trunk</tt>
    </subsection>

    <subsection title="Static Binaries">
      These are statically linked binaries, that means they run
      without any extra requiremed libraries (except X11 and a
      GNU/Linux box). [Note: static binaries are no longer provided,
      since compilation should be relativly easy, if there is any
      demand for them I could start providing them again.]

      <downloads>
	<item file="construo-0.0.2-binary-i386.tar.gz">outdated binary release, not recomment</item>
      </downloads>
    </subsection>

    <subsection title="Additional Constructions">
      Additional constructions, contributed by Construo users:
      
      <downloads>
	<item file="choh2.tar.bz2">Construo House of Horror 2 - A collection of 9 new torture machines by Mark Michelsen (already included in 0.2.0)</item>
	<item file="choh.tar.bz2">Construo House of Horror - A collection of 9 torture machines by Mark Michelsen  (already included in 0.2.0)</item>
      </downloads>      
    </subsection>

    <subsection title="Links">
      <ul>
        <li><a
               href="http://www.cs.rutgers.edu/~decarlo/software.html">xspringies
            - Another piece of GPLed software, pretty similar to this one</a></li>
        <li>
          <a href="https://savannah.nongnu.org/projects/construo/">Savannah Project Page</a>
        </li>
        <li>
          <a href="http://savannah.nongnu.org/download/construo/doxygen/">Construo Source Code Documentation</a>
        </li>

      </ul>
    </subsection>

  </section>

  <copyright/>
</page>
